Register of the San Diego Aerospace Museum collection circa 1860-1946
Hoover Institution Archives
San Diego Aerospace Museum collection
circa 1860-1946
2002C70
San Diego Aerospace Museum.
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Photographs, postcards, and miscellany, relating mainly to American participation in World Wars I and II. Collected by the San Diego Aerospace Museum.
2 oversize boxes (2.7 linear feet)
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
Access to audiovisual materials requires at least two weeks advance notice. Audiovisual materials include sound recordings, video recordings, and motion picture film. Hoover staff will determine whether use copies of the materials requested can be made available. Some materials may not be accessible even with advance notice. Please contact the Hoover Institution Archives for further information.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2002.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Historical Note
1962 October 12 Established when the State of California approved the articles of incorporation
1963 February Museum opened
1964 March International Aerospace Hall of Fame (IAHF) established
Circa 1965 Museum moved to the Electric Building, which provided more area for display
1978 February Fire destroyed aircraft, artifacts, and archival materials
1980 February Museum re-opened
1986 Became the first aero-themed museum to be accredited by the American Association of Museums
2006 Name changed to the San Diego Air & Space Museum Museum acquired the Low Speed Wind Tunnel
Source: San Diego Air & Space Museum website. Accessed through http://www.sandiegoairandspace.org/
Scope and Content of Collection
In 2002, the San Diego Aerospace Museum, now known as the San Diego Air and Space Museum, donated materials to the Hoover Institution Archives that matched the archives' collecting goals. The San Diego Aerospace Museum collection contains photographs and postcards mainly related to American participation in World Wars I and II.
The collection includes images from a range of conflicts, from the American Civil War to World War II. There are full-page clippings of Civil War cartoons, including drawings by Theodore R. Davis. One photo album contains images of World War I soldiers, while a photo album presented to William Korongy from the 1939-1940 New York World's Fair includes photographs of the January 28 Incident, also known as the Shanghai War of 1932.
Some of the photographs related to World War II originated from the Theodore Blaine collection at the museum. Materials include a service record detailing where Blaine was stationed, which provides context for the photographs of American soldiers in France during World War II.
Additional photographs depicting the World War II era include scenes of Italy and Southern France, which were donated to the museum by Bob Bower.
San Diego Aerospace Museum.; United States. Army. American Expeditionary Forces.; United States--Armed Forces.; World War, 1914-1918; World War, 1939-1945.
- American Red Cross map of London, undated (Box 1)
- Civil War cartoon clippings, circa 1860s (Box 1)
  Full page drawings. Includes drawings by Theodore R. Davis, Alexander Simplot, A.R. Waud, H. Mosler, Frank Beard, and Stanley Fox
- Pamphlet for Camp Myles Standish, Boston Port of Embarkation, undated (Box 1)
- Photo album presented to William Korongy from 1939-1940 New York World's Fair, 1924-1940, undated (Box 1)
  Includes images of war, including photographs of Shanghai and conflicts between China and Japan, such as the January 28 Incident, also known as the Shanghai War of 1932. Includes loose photographs of Hawaii and World Fair ticket stub.
- Photo album of Iowa State College and World War I soldiers, 1910s-1920s (Box 1)
  Includes loose photographic prints and negatives
- Photographs, undated (Box 1)
  Increment from 2002
- Photographs and postcards, World War II, 1945, undated (Box 1)
  Includes images of London, the American Red Cross, and American soldiers in France
- Postcards, undated (Box 1)
  Includes images of Belgium and the United States
- Service record of Theodore Blaine from 1942 to 1945 (Box 1)
- Photograph of North Atlantic Route Service Conference, Dublin, 1946 (Box 2)
- Photographs of Italy and Southern France, World War II, 1944, undated (Box 2)